{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Preppy","incorrectAnswers":["Grunge","Hippie","Gothic"],"question":"What is the name of the fashion trend popularized in the 1950s that involves wearing cardigans, loafers, and pleated skirts?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Full Dark, No Stars'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Maroon","Black","Gold"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of New Zealand?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Apollo","incorrectAnswers":["Hermes","Artemis","Morpheus"],"question":"Who was the Greek God of prophecy & archery, music & healing, light & truth, agriculture and cattle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jean-François Millet","incorrectAnswers":["Gustav Klimt","Pablo Picasso","Cassius Marcellus Coolidge"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Gleaners\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Crimean","incorrectAnswers":["World War I","Napoleonic","US War of Independence"],"question":"With Which War Is Florence Nightingale Associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cherry","incorrectAnswers":["Mango","Papaya","Pineapple"],"question":"Which of these fruits is not a tropical fruit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Golf","incorrectAnswers":["Cycling","Surfing","Figure skating"],"question":"With which sport is Annika Sörenstam associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mogadishu","incorrectAnswers":["Timbuktu","Bakar","Addis Ababa"],"question":"What is the capital of Somalia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Natalie Portman","incorrectAnswers":["Annette Bening","Nicole Kidman","Jennifer Lawrence"],"question":"Who won the 2010 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Nina Sayers/The Swan Queen in Black Swan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bumfuzzle","incorrectAnswers":["Oxter","Cattywampus","Quire"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'confused, perplexed'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Maple Tree","incorrectAnswers":["Oak Tree","Birch Tree","Elm Tree"],"question":"Which type of tree is known for its association with Canada and its bright red foliage in autumn?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Charles Darwin","incorrectAnswers":["Admiral Nelson","Francis Drake","Christopher Columbus"],"question":"Who was aboard the H.M.S. Beagle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Iran","Austria","Algeria"],"question":"Which of these countries was once part of the British Empire?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hula","incorrectAnswers":["Tango","Flamenco","Salsa"],"question":"What is the dance traditionally performed by Hawaiian women?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Cuban Missile Crisis","incorrectAnswers":["The Suez Crisis","The Bay of Pigs Invasion","The Gulf War"],"question":"Which event led John F Kennedy to announce a naval blockade on October 22, 1962?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Remains of the Day","incorrectAnswers":["Post Office","Heart of Darkness","Lucky Jim"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Stevens'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"John F Kennedy","incorrectAnswers":["Winston Churchill","Henry VIII","Josef Stalin"],"question":"Who Was Quoted As Saying \"Ask Not What Your Country Can Do For You But What You Can Do For Your Country''?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Quidditch","incorrectAnswers":["Rumple Grump","Twizzlesticks","Nimbrod"],"question":"In Harry Potter, what is the name of the magical sport that is played on broomsticks?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lovin' You","incorrectAnswers":["Pass the Dutchie","In My House","Funkytown"],"question":"What song did Minnie Riperton have a hit with in 1974?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"George Lucas","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Star Wars: Episode III – Revenge of the Sith?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Three equal vertical bands of blue white and red.","incorrectAnswers":["Three equal horizontal bands of red white and red.","Blue with a red cross outlined in white extending to the edges.","White with a large red disk in the center."],"question":"What does the flag of France look like?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"John Locke","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Paul Sartre","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Friedrich Nietzsche"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'The mind is furnished with ideas by experience alone'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Visa","incorrectAnswers":["Zurich","Mastercard","HSBC"],"question":"'Everywhere you want to be' is a slogan associated with which finance brand?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Bonn","incorrectAnswers":["Munich","Berlin","Frankfurt"],"question":"Which German city served as the capital of West Germany from 1949 until reunification in 1990?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hakodate","incorrectAnswers":["Ōsaka","Kyoto","Yokohama"],"question":"Which city used to be called Zenigamezawa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Rudyard Kipling","incorrectAnswers":["Shel Silverstein","Dr. Seuss","Wilson Rawls"],"question":"Who wrote the Jungle Book?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pampas","incorrectAnswers":["Andes","Patagonia","Sierra"],"question":"Which of these is a huge flat region of plains in Argentina?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Portugal ","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Spain","France"],"question":"Which country produces the wine Vinho Verdi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Naomi Watts","incorrectAnswers":["Melissa Leo","Frances Conroy","Laura Linney"],"question":"Which actress has starred in both Birdman and King Kong?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Joe Pesci","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Shaw","Bruce Willis","Errol Flynn"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Tommy DeVito in GoodFellas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"While there is life there is hope","incorrectAnswers":["Wisdom is power","Every man is the maker of his own fortune","So it begins"],"question":"What is the meaning of the Latin phrase 'Dum vita est, spes est'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Buffy the Vampire Slayer","incorrectAnswers":["Sabrina, the Teenage Witch","Charmed","Supernatural"],"question":"On which TV series did Alyson Hannigan play a geek-turned-witch?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lilongwe","incorrectAnswers":["Brasilia","Male","Ouagadougou"],"question":"What is the capital city of Malawi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"I Melt With You","incorrectAnswers":["Rock And Roll (Part 2)","867-5309 - Jenny","How Do You Talk to an Angel?"],"question":"Modern English had a one hit wonder in 1984 with which song?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A Streetcar Named Desire","incorrectAnswers":["Psycho","12 Angry Men","Gone with the Wind"],"question":"What movie from 1951 includes the quote \"I have always depended on the kindness of strangers\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Disgusting things","incorrectAnswers":["Crayfish","Plant nutrition","Earthquakes"],"question":"What is Grossology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Taiwan","incorrectAnswers":["South Korea","Malaysia","Philippines"],"question":"Tainan is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ebenezer Scrooge","incorrectAnswers":["Charles Dickens","Bob Cratchit","Uriah Heep"],"question":"What is the name of the miserly main character in A Christmas Carol?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kylie Minogue","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Mika","Hikaru Utada"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'I Should Be So Lucky'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Three equal horizontal bands of red white and red.","incorrectAnswers":["Three equal vertical bands of green, yellow, and red.","Red field with a yellow sun in the center.","Green with a yellow diamond in the center with a blue celestial globe."],"question":"What does the flag of Austria look like?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Miata","incorrectAnswers":["The Mustang","The Camaro","The Corvette"],"question":"What is the name of the sports car introduced by Mazda in 1989?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Nebula","incorrectAnswers":["Eitri","Shuri","Pepper Potts"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Karen Gillan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"ABBA","incorrectAnswers":["In Flames","HammerFall","Katatonia"],"question":"Which Swedish pop group released the song 'The Winner Takes It All'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lewis Carroll","incorrectAnswers":["Enid Blyton","George Orwell","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Through the Looking-Glass'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Three horizontal bands of sky blue, white, and sky blue, with a yellow sun in the center.","incorrectAnswers":["Red with a white cross that extends to the edges.","Two equal horizontal bands of white and red.","Red with a yellow sun having eight broadening rays extending to the edges."],"question":"What does the flag of Argentina look like?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ice Cube","incorrectAnswers":["Eminem","50 Cent","Snoop Dogg"],"question":"Which of these musicians was a member of NWA?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Pauciloquent","incorrectAnswers":["Grommet","Lackadaisical","Borborygmus"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'uttering few words; brief in speech'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Calgary Flames","incorrectAnswers":["Calgary Thunder","Calgary Bears","Calgary Royals"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Calgary?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A quatrain","incorrectAnswers":["A sonnet","A haiku","A couplet"],"question":"In poetry, what is the name for a 4-line stanza?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Democratic Republic of the Congo","incorrectAnswers":["Gabon","Equatorial Guinea","Rwanda"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Central African Republic?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Ethiopia","incorrectAnswers":["Nigeria","South Africa","Egypt"],"question":"Which African country did Menelik II help unite into its modern form, when he was emperor until 1913?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Friedrich Schiller","incorrectAnswers":["Sebastian Brant","Agatha Christie","Rainer Maria Rilke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Robbers'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Bosnia & Herzegovina","Greece","Sweden"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Saint Petersburg?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kazakhstan","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Tajikistan","Uzbekistan"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Russia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Heraclitus","incorrectAnswers":["Baruch Spinoza","Denis Diderot","Ludwig Wittgenstein"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'One cannot step twice in the same river'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"hair and scalp","incorrectAnswers":["angels","the ecology of plant communities","sleep"],"question":"What is Trichology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Botswana","incorrectAnswers":["Malawi","Eswatini","Lesotho"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Zimbabwe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A pace","incorrectAnswers":["A cast","A pride","A brace"],"question":"What is the word for a group of asses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Dionysus","incorrectAnswers":["Aphrodite","Isis","Bacchus"],"question":"Who was the Greek god of wine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"King Arthur","incorrectAnswers":["Robin Hood","Boudicca","Alfred the Great"],"question":"Who lived at Camelot?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"John Locke","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Denis Diderot","Socrates"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'It is one thing to show a man that he is in error, and another to put him in possession of truth'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Amazon","incorrectAnswers":["The Ganges","The Loire","The Mekong"],"question":"What is the world's widest river?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Pluperfect","incorrectAnswers":["Past perfect","Present perfect","Future perfect"],"question":"What word refers to the tense used in phrases like 'she had departed'.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Oxford University","incorrectAnswers":["Jerusalem","Cape Town","Bethlehem"],"question":"Where was Methodism founded?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jai Ho","incorrectAnswers":["My Heart Will Go On","Let It Go","Shallow"],"question":"What Oscar-winning song was featured in the 2008 movie 'Slumdog Millionaire'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"J. Robert Oppenheimer","incorrectAnswers":["Albert Einstein","Enrico Fermi","Edward Teller"],"question":"Which scientist is known as \"the father of the atomic bomb\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A stud","incorrectAnswers":["A cete","A paddling","A troop"],"question":"What is the word for a group of mares?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yellow","incorrectAnswers":["Maroon","White","Blue"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Vietnam?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Narwhal","incorrectAnswers":["Beluga","Orca","Humpback"],"question":"What is the name of the unicorn-like whale whose ‘horn’ is actually a long tusk?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Macbeth","incorrectAnswers":["Richard III","Hamlet","Romeo & Juliet"],"question":"Name the Shakespeare play from this plot summary: \"Urged on by his wife, a man murders his king in order to take his place\".","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Jinmen Gaoliang","incorrectAnswers":["Bourbon","Riga Black Balsam","Chibuku"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Taiwan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"IRAC","incorrectAnswers":["HAL","OPAL","TRON"],"question":"What was the name of the computer in TV's Wonder Woman?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Athena","incorrectAnswers":["Apollo","Aphrodite","Hercules"],"question":"In Greek mythology, who turned Arachne into a spider?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"White","incorrectAnswers":["Red","Green","Blue"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Qatar?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sterilization","incorrectAnswers":["Pain relief","Anesthesia","Radiography"],"question":"What was the medical first performed by Joseph Lister using carbolic acid on his surgical instruments?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bells","incorrectAnswers":["Violins","Trumpets","Ukeleles"],"question":"What type of musical instrument is featured in the theme song of \"Futurama\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Franc","incorrectAnswers":["Peso","Dollar","Gira"],"question":"What is the basic unit of currency for Equatorial Guinea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Raw","incorrectAnswers":["Fried","Boiled","Grilled"],"question":"How is steak tartare cooked?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"12","incorrectAnswers":["4","10","8"],"question":"How many faces does a dodecahedron have?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Cyprus","incorrectAnswers":["Ireland","Sicily","Corsica"],"question":"Formed in 1955, with which island was the organisation known by the acronym EOKA associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Quintuplets","incorrectAnswers":["Triplets","Sextuplets","Octuplets"],"question":"What is the word used when a mother gives birth to 5 babies?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Coldplay","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British band released the studio album 'Mylo Xyloto'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Netherlands","incorrectAnswers":["Greece","Malta","Bulgaria"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Three equal horizontal bands of red white and blue.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"My mother thanks you. My father thanks you. My sister thanks you. And I thank you.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Here's Johnny!\"","\"I’m going to have to science the s*** out of this.\"","\"May the Force be with you.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Yankee Doodle Dandy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Heart And Soul","incorrectAnswers":["Electric Avenue","Smokin' in the Boys Room","Seasons in the Sun"],"question":"T'Pau had a one hit wonder in 1987 with which song?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sally Hawkins","incorrectAnswers":["Lucy Lawless","Abigail Breslin","Kim Basinger"],"question":"Which actress has starred in both The Shape of Water and Vera Drake?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Rober Peary","incorrectAnswers":["Mungo Park","Henry Hudson","Kit Carson"],"question":"Who was the first person to reach the North Pole?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Rhetoric","incorrectAnswers":["Didactic","Syntax","Semantics"],"question":"What is the term for the art or study of using language to persuade, which comes from the Greek word for \"orator\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Portland Trailblazers","incorrectAnswers":["Portland Wizards","Portland Hornets","Portland Orioles"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Portland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Yellow","incorrectAnswers":["Red","Black","Blue"],"question":"In Italian, what is the meaning of the word 'giallo'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cherry ","incorrectAnswers":["Plum","Apple","Orange"],"question":"Which fruit goes into the liqueur Kirsch?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jules Verne","incorrectAnswers":["Victor Hugo","Alphonse Daudet","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Adventures of Captain Hatteras'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Battle of Balaclava","incorrectAnswers":["Battle of Waterloo","Battle of Leipzig","Battle of Smolensk"],"question":"At which battle was the Charge Of The Light Brigade?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"2009","incorrectAnswers":["2003","2005","2007"],"question":"In which year was Inglourious Basterds first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Baseball","incorrectAnswers":["Basketball","Football","Soccer"],"question":"What sport is played at Wrigley Field in Chicago?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Driving Miss Daisy","incorrectAnswers":["Born on the Fourth of July","Dead Poets Society","Field of Dreams"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1989?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Prism","incorrectAnswers":["Lens","Polarizer","Funnel"],"question":"What is the name for a piece of glass that separates light into the visible spectrum?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Everglades","incorrectAnswers":["Yellowstone","Yosemite","Grand Canyon"],"question":"Which subtropical American national park established in 1947 is known to harbor alligators?","difficulty":"medium"},